we're starting this episode on a journey
to somewhere that isn't my base or
indeed any project that i'm currently
working on there's a joke that i've been
meaning to do since the beginning of
season seven and there it is this is
where we're heading ethos base and
basically all i wanted to do is a joke
that i'm sure he's never heard before
i'm 100 certain this is a joke that he's
never seen guess what that is that's a
slab now now it's an etho slab
i don't even know if he's gonna get this
i'm so childish then i started taking a
look around here and i've come to
realize how
peculiar whoa there's an anime beat ups
you don't see that every day do you i
feel like i'm giving i'm now just
straight up giving a tour of ethos base
we've got to do this properly
hermit crib style
ethos base is a modern 2020 masterpiece
of madness he's got everything he's got
the honeycombs
and he's got
whatever those things are the interior
comes packed with plenty of storage
including all of his clocks and herbs
somehow etho manages to bring the
outside on the inside only the the
slickest hermits have a llama are going
around their base and he remains the
only hermit to have somehow made a house
made completely of interiors
how is this possible this base confuses
me but it wouldn't be an episode of
hermit cribs without talking about the
productivity of the base etho is no
stranger to redstone and by looking at
all of this armpit smell you always find
something new in ethos base
he's got easy dispensing dies
that's not dice he's got bubble
elevators that lead to
the outside and of course a place
for his infinite musical prowess i feel
like this could be a b-side show hermit
cribs just green turns up and has a look
at what your base is doing
and just gives it a score i mean this is
the most confusing yet intriguing bass
i've ever encountered i think i think
we've got to give this a rating there's
both a massive attention to detail as
he's got little cubby holes where you
can just sit and have a relax and then
he's got functionality the color palette
is actually really pleasing but somehow
and i don't really understand how he's
built inside first
and then when you just when you hit the
outside that's it the building just
stops
it just ends green's hermit crib
final result nine out of ten
a beautiful mess whose base should we
review next that kind of just came out
of nowhere i feel like we could do that
more often green's herb at cribs where
we just go and have a look at other
people's bases and just just rate it out
of ten i really like ethos bass even
though it's the most unconventional
thing i've ever seen on the hermitcraft
server whose base should we go
and rate next and at some point we could
even critique our own base
and give this a score out of 10. but we
need to get on with our episode now i
have been planning quite a lot i've got
shulker boxes full of the materials for
the next part of the build but i also
said that i wanted to use the rest of
this tnt to gather more netherright and
truly take the crown of the netherright
king
back to the upside down we go
whoa
someone blew up my diagonal tunnel
and what's this
down the tunnel makes it look like
you're falling
falling all the way to the upside down
now i haven't been here in a while so i
don't know if anyone has taken me up on
my offer
to live in the upside down we invited
three people we invited mumbo b-dubs and
scar
and we're still alone friends can be
hard to come by sometimes i sent out
birthday invites to all of my friends
and no one showed up well i'm sure
someone will turn up eventually so
let's just continue right we want to go
and find a fresh place to dig
underground lava free
and get ourselves more netherright so
let's start here and see where we get to
as most people know netherright occurs
the most at y15 now i have been digging
a bit lower than y15 because i'm
terrified of blowing up the ceiling
and having the lava pour down on me but
this time i'm going to try placing the
tnt yeah like that i'm gonna try placing
the tnt
a little bit higher and seeing if i get
more results or if i just release all of
the lava oh my goodness this is just
just a bit here
let's do a very quick test
and see if the results are any better
begone nether
yeah
quite a lot of lava
so far so good actually i think that was
a total of five veins of ancient debris
but a lot of them only had one in so
that's pretty good going
now i think what we need to do
is go
full time lapse mode
and get rid of as much nether as
possible
using the tnt method
let's go
[Applause]
uh
[Music]
[Applause]
i think i found the scariest minecraft
head after all that i i acquired one of
these and i just the more you look into
their eyes the more sort of creepy it
gets until
i found this one oh it's so much worse
look into
these eyes i think this is the creepiest
minecraft head i've ever seen however i
did find one two three
four stacks of ancient debris plus seven
and then i've got a little bit left over
we need to get this
i don't know if i want to
turn all of it into scrap and then
ingots i might keep a little bit of
ancient debris as debris and maybe sell
some but let's get most of this
smelting up and transformed into
something useful
it's a bit like watching paint dry
actually
it's taking a while
there we go all the near the right scrap
now
how much do we get out of this
only 59 ingots
and that is
six blocks of netherrite
the most expensive item in the game
i spent several hours and i've got
six of them
i could get more
by smelting this up i think we've got to
commit now in order to call myself the
netherright king i at least need enough
for a throne
i may have to cheat a little bit
by adding some ancient debris as the
back
boom the netherright throne it's not
quite as spectacular as the diamond
throne but it's still got some sort of
sense of power i think it's just because
these are so rare a little bit
lackluster isn't it but check it out
great whoa
i forgot i was wearing this check it out
i am with all
of my tools and armor the netherright
king i did lose unfortunately some
netherite along the way i don't really
know how i'll probably find it at some
point but i i'm probably missing at
least a stack maybe more
just because i had to do so many trips
with tnt and such but check it out we
are
the netherright king for all of your
netherrite needs you come to me
so what are we gonna do with all of this
netherright
well i was thinking what we could do
is resurrect
the did you die box but instead of
calling it the did you die box
i think we should just call it the
backup box
i think it's got a nice ring to it and
we'll sell the backup boxes at the barge
i'll probably only make a couple to
begin with and then from there we'll see
we'll see if we sell a couple they're
going to be
very
very expensive
i'm going to quickly redesign this
so that i can constantly have the
netherite throne i won't use all of my
netherrite because this is gonna go in
the main base
so the netherright throne will look
like
this
boom
slightly less powerful but these are
expensive
each block represents a couple of hours
excise my void is actually
not selling he's just throwing away
stuff and he's giving me coordinates to
go meet him because he's just throwing
away stacks and stacks of stuff and i'm
like no i'll take that yeah we'll take a
couple of shulker boxes with us
we'll take the netherright throne with
us as well okay the netherright throne
is definitely not something you can take
around very quickly this this this stuff
is uh painful to mine if i press tab you
can see my score going up so even though
it says i got 500 it's not particularly
accurate because as you can see it's
going up and this isn't uh this isn't
naturally generated never right this is
obviously what i've gotten placed so
those numbers are not particularly
accurate especially if you built
anything with netherrite so don't take
those numbers too seriously what you
really gotta look out for is how many
blocks of netherrite have they got so if
we fly this direction for a little bit
we should come across some free goodies
oh there he is lots of leather and pork
chops i'm here to take your stuff look
at all this leather i've i'm gonna sell
this as item frames in the barge i have
not been able to stock it for a while
there is there's so much
i don't i don't think i need this much
leather this is insane okay maybe i
don't even think i need this much
leather to be fair but you know free
stuff why throw it out well that was a
pretty good deal now let's head back to
the base
and make our first backup box whoa
scar has been
busy he's a little bit late to the
nether game but
look at that what a magnificent looking
build i think the perfect place for the
netherright throne is right here i think
we need a glowing pedestal so that it's
raised off the ground boom the
netherright throne oh that looks so epic
i mean it's a tiny chair but it's a
powerful chair it's a very expensive
chair so we have 27
ingots of netherrite to play with which
will get us pretty far when it comes to
making our backup boxes to sell
on the barge
so this is really easy for the most part
i just basically trade up some emeralds
easy peasy trade up the emeralds then i
buy one piece of each armor the
enchantments don't matter particularly
one of each tool unenchant all of them
so i'm left with the components
then go back
and upgrade them
although i don't think a chest plate is
particularly needed no one wears chest
plates so that might be just a waste of
netherrite
so we'll do the legs the feet
and the helmet and then of course the
tools
place them all in a box and then we put
in everything else that you will require
if you happen to somehow lose all your
netherrite gear i have a feeling people
will like this just to have a spare
backup because if you die
you obviously come back to your base
without anything and then you've got to
go and find all your stuff and often if
you died it's probably because something
got you probably one of these and they
hit hard so having a spare set of armor
is one of those things that takes a lot
of effort but it's only needed
occasionally
i don't have any toolsmiths here at all
so
a sword might have to be left out of
this maybe this is a backup box mark one
we'll see if this sells if it doesn't
then we'll start enchanting the stuff up
and adding the swords and everything
else but for now i think that's pretty
good you got your wings you got your
carrots
you got all the tools and you got the
armor
so now the question is
what do we sell them for oh well let me
just do some quick thinking on this each
inger is for ancient debris
now ancient debris is very hard to come
by we're looking at
i think we're looking at a cool 200
diamonds for one of these 200 diamonds
maybe even more maybe i've just
undersold this completely i keep meaning
to do work here i need to finish this
what is what is this shop it looks it
looks like a cinnamon roll
a boxed cinnamon roll actually no it
might be ancient debris oh wait yeah
there we go
it totally sells ancient debris
one diamond block person oh he is
actually calling them cinnamon buns
press button for more cinnamon buns
one diamond block
for one ancient nether debris
oh wow okay so maybe i did completely
undersell with this in mind you'd have
to mine one two three four to get a
single ingot so that is
he almost doubles my price okay based on
my new price it's going to be
220 diamonds for this this is
unenchanted so this is the the prototype
backup box and i could even sell these
whoa
blimey
do you mind i could even sell these
individually for a little bit more to
encourage people to buy the backup box
all right we need to put this on a bit
of a pedestal because this is an
important box we want to draw some
attention to it
diamonds that is a deal
oh my god oh i thought the shulker box
was going to stay there for a second it
looks mighty impressive
haven't actually checked the barge in a
while see if we've got any profits
oh it's happened
it's happened we finally sold some dirt
but we finally sold some dirt
you have no idea how happy that makes me
we just sold literal dirt i don't think
i don't think you'd realize how big of a
deal that is we have made so many sales
i need to restock
i really need to restock
another cool 36 diamonds to the
ever-growing pile of diamonds in the
chest actually let's turn these into
blocks
54 diamond blocks that is a lot
so we just need someone to buy this and
if they don't we'll have to consider
adding even more stuff in here and then
probably upping the price even more
tell all your friends the backup box is
back in business
the the back puns are gonna be big for
this one back-to-back sales
the boxes
they're back
i think i'll be back to restock this in
another episode because it's uh it's
quite the task doing all this and i also
want to add some more stock i'll come up
with some other things i can do come on
someone buy the backup box actually the
new stock is very simple we're just
going to
fill up because we are the netherright
king now
we are going to fill up on all
netherrite tools for the barge all
unenchanted but mainly because
i don't want to uh steal business from
lucky looking at my bookie from corrales
so we just do the same thing with all of
these tools
and a little bit spare
one of these is going to set you back
32 diamonds
boom
we may expand this but this is a very
very expensive line of items
i think we have a potential customer
let's watch le let's let's watch your
average customer
in the wild here we see
the wild iskal checking out the bargains
in barge
displeased he moves around
the prices are obviously
not right
perhaps he'll be back
another time mamba was like hey iskall
just stealing some slime he's like
there's a shot but okay and i was like
yeah and i was like oh do we need to we
need to tell him when we take stuff i've
also just realized i'm now out of
netherrite so this entire episode was
spent
getting the netherright throne
and then running out i think all that
has led to me running out of time
due to the the lengthy process it takes
to find all of this ancient debris so
for now i'm gonna have to say thank you
very much for watching
and good
bye but not really goodbye because i
just wanted to have a quick word with
everybody and say that you may have
noticed that my videos have been a
little bit further apart than usual i'm
normally you know only three or four
days apart between each episode however
recently it's been more like a week
maybe even a few days more than that and
that's pretty simply because i'm just
really swamped at the moment in real
life i've got a lot going on a lot of
stresses and i'm trying to do a lot to
keep myself going and i'm finding it
incredibly difficult to get on
hermitcraft and get on minecraft and
make my other videos i've got loads of
stuff in the pipeline i'm just not
getting enough time into them this
episode itself was even a minute shorter
than it should have been hence why we're
having this conversation right now so i
just wanted to thank everybody for their
patience and not bugging me about it
because i really am doing my best and
trying to get out as many videos as
possible so i just want to say a huge
huge thank you to every single one of
you
and goodbye for real this time